なんば　むった
せんばつ
なぞ
(南波六太)＜宇宙飛行士選抜 謎の
最終試験を直前に➡
I, Nanba Mutta, age 32, await the upcoming, mysterious final astronaut selection exam.
ひか
わたくし
さい
控えた私 南波六太 ３２歳＞
While Apo and I watched Hibito pass overhead in a T-38,
ひびと
＜アポと私が 弟･日々人の乗る
Ｔ－３８を見上げていた頃＞
＜私の父と母はヒューストンへ
向けて飛び立とうとしていた＞
my mother and father were flying to Houston.
Moving on, let's get going.
なすだ
(茄子田)それは さておき 皆さん
まいりましょう｡➡
Onward to Houston!
いざ ヒューストンへ～！
I will rise,
climb,
and shoot through the atmosphere
My goal is zero gravity
Space Brothers
Waves of people flood the intersection
Like vague silhouettes they stream past incessantly
How do I look in their midst?
I don't know
Hiding my true intentions desperately
I dish out vague excuses
My ambitions of going to space, harbored for so long,
are frail and brittle
No matter how I turn the globus
I have no home where I end up
There's no point to looking on a map
I will rise,
climb,
and shoot through the atmosphere
until I can look down on the entire world
I will yell
and scream
with a heart of steel
that I am going to zero gravity
#26 Painful Interview
You're so cute...
(南波母)かわいいわね～｡
あなたがアポちゃんね｡
You must be Apo.
There, there, there.
ふふふ うふふ｡
He's ugly...
ぶさいく…というよりは…｡
Or should I say
ぶちゃいくだな｡
うふふ｡
cugly?
２人ともカゼとか
ひいてないだろうな？
Neither of you is sick, right?
ＮＡＳＡの面会検査で
ウイルスでも見つかったら➡
If you test positive for a virus,
打ち上げ前に日々人に
会えなくなるからな｡
you won't get to see Hibito on the day before launch.
分かってる？
大丈夫よ！そんなもん｡
Got it?
I'll be just fine!
Don't worry.
心配すんな｡
今 人生で一番健康だ｡
I've never been healthier in my life.
あんたこそ 明日 本番なんでしょ｡
体調は いいの？
Isn't tomorrow your big day?
How are you feeling?
ふっ！ふふふ…｡
昨日 スクワットを２１６回
やったのに な～んともない！
I did two hundred, sixteen squats yesterday, and I feel just fine!
２１６回…｡
ハンパだな➡
Two hundred and sixteen?
Such a half-assed number.
You couldn't manage four more?
あと４回ぐらい
なんとか なんなかったのか｡
うひょ～｡
かくり
あ～あ 日々人は今頃 隔離されて
何やってんのかしら｡
I wonder what Hibito's doing in quarantine.
いいな～隔離｡私も一度
隔離とか されてみたいわぁ～｡
It sounds so fun.
I'd like to be quarantined once in my life.
《この人達は日々人が宇宙へ
行ってもこんな感じなんだろか》
Is this how they'll be, once Hibito's in space?
Final Exam
Johnson Space Center
(紫)おっ ミヤッチ 見て見て！
来たよ！来なすったよ これ！
Ooh!
Check this out, Miya-chi!
He's finally here.
Astronaut
Murasaki Sansei (37)
日々人の兄ちゃん！
マジで残ったってか！
It's Hibito's big brother.
He made it through!
Astronaut
Miyata Atsushi (38)
さすが兄弟…といったところか｡
He is Hibito's brother, after all.
They're brothers, but they look nothing alike.
兄弟っつっても似てね～よ ほら！
Look.
想像してたのと 全然 違うもん！
He doesn't look how I expected.
Astronaut
Kizaki Sanae (38)
(木崎)想像って？
(紫)やっぱ兄ちゃんだけに…｡
What did you expect?
They're brothers, so I figured he'd be...
⦅失礼しま～す⦆
Excuse me.
Ah!
⦅あ…⦆
くふふ｡
楽しそう｡
You're enjoying yourself.
どんな男か楽しみではある｡
I'm interested in finding out what he's like.
Huh?
Azuma, your seat is over here.
あずま
あれ？吾妻さんの席は
こっち側ですよ｡
(吾妻)俺は ここでいい｡
I'll sit here.
I know how this interview is supposed to work.
この面接が どういうものかは
わかってるよ｡
ここまで来れたお兄ちゃんが
もし選ばれなかったとしたら➡
If this guy isn't chosen in the end,
その最大の要因は 日々人より
先に来なかったことだな｡➡
the main reason will be because he was following Hibito.
かわいそうに｡
Poor guy.
な 何するんだ？
Wh-What are you doing?
Oh...
ちょっと！紫くん｡
Wait, Murasaki!
いいから いいから｡
It'll be fine...
どこのネジかは知らないけど➡
I don't know which screw it was before, but Nanba Mutta apparently noticed it was loose.
ゆるんだイスのネジに気付いた
らしいんだよね｡南波六太は｡
Hoshika used this tactic in the actual exam.
ほしか
じっせん
星加さんが実践したらしい｡
ホントに!?
Really?
That should do it.
こんなもんかな｡
何も そこまでしなくて いいのに｡
You don't need to loosen it that much.
(紫)いいじゃないか｡
これくらいの遊び｡
I don't see a problem with having a little fun.
本当に気付く奴なのか どうか
見たいじゃん｡
Don't you want to see if he really notices?
それに…
この面接自体…あれだろ？
Besides...
This interview is just...
You know?
南波さんは座らないんですか？
Aren't you going to sit, Nanba?
Huh?
Nah, I'm good, Serika.
うん 大丈夫だよ｡せりかさん｡
《相変わらず かわいい人だなぁ➡
She's so cute...
Makes my nostrils flare.
鼻も ふくらむぜ》
Actually, Serika...
《実はね せりかさん 座らないん
じゃなくて 座れないんだよ》
It isn't that I don't want to sit. I really can't.
《１日遅れで…
俺の足腰 超筋肉痛！》
My legs started to ache a day late!
Eddie Jay...
⦅エディ…ジェイ➡
あずまたきお！ハァハァ➡
Azuma Takio!
南波～！日々人～！⦆
Nanba...
Hibito!
⦅昨日 スクワットを２１６回も
やったのに な～んともない！⦆
I did two hundred, sixteen squats yesterday, and I feel just fine!
⦅あひゃぁ～⦆
《一度 座ったら
しなん
立ち上がるのは至難のワザ》
If I sit down now, standing back up will be extremely difficult.
にった
(新田)面接のトップバッターに
なったもんだから➡
He's the first one up, so he's probably nervous.
落ち着かないんだろ｡
《うるせ～新田》
Shut up, Nitta!
Mr. Mutta.
(担当者)ミスター･ムッタ｡
イ･イエス！
Y-Yes!
Okay, let's go.
ＯＫ 行きましょう｡
Well, I'm off, then.
じゃあ お先に行ってくるよ｡
(ケンジ)がんばって｡
Good luck.
The interview itself isn't that important.
《最大のポイントは
面接そのものじゃない➡
What matters is when I stand up at the end.
終了後 イスから
立ち上がる時だな》
《意地でも
笑顔をキープしてやる｡➡
I have to keep a smile on my face.
I definitely can't let them know that my muscles are aching.
みじん
筋肉痛であることは 微塵も
感じさせてなるものか！》
(野口さん)はい どうぞ｡
Come in.
失礼します！南波六太です！
Hello, I'm Nanba Mutta!
うおあ！
はい こんにちは｡
宇宙飛行士の野口聡一です｡
Hello, I am astronaut Noguchi Soichi.
ヒューストンにようこそ｡
南波六太君｡
Welcome to Houston, Nanba Mutta.
はい！
《すっごい！野口さんだ！➡
Right!
Wow... It's Noguchi!
In the flesh!
本物だ！》
《うおおおお！野口さんの隣には
若田さん 星出さん➡
Wakata and Hoshide are next to Noguchi!
うえええ～ヤバイだろ～➡
This is crazy!
Kisaki... Miyata.
木崎さん 宮田さん
紫さんまでいる！》
Even Murasaki is here!
Amazing... They're all real astronauts.
《すごい みんな宇宙飛行士だ➡
Isn't Azuma here?
あれ？吾妻さんは
いないのか？》
これから宇宙飛行士選抜試験の
最後の面接をします｡➡
We will now begin the final interview of the astronaut selection exam.
You may feel nervous, but we want to learn more about you.
緊張してるかも しれないけども
僕たちは君の事を知りたいから➡
リラックスして
色々と楽しんでください｡
So please relax and enjoy yourself.
はい！
(野口さん)じゃあ 座って下さい｡
Yes!
Please have a seat.
はい！
Yes!
主な質問は こちらから するので
この向きで座って下さい｡
We will be asking most of the questions, so please face us.
はい！
《ん？》
Yes.
It'll take one second to sit. Clench!
《座るのは一瞬だ！勝負！》
《あいててて…》
Ouch...
《うっ…くっ》
Ow...
Whew...
《ふ～》
《ん？んんっ!?》
Hmm?
《あ～吾妻さんだ》
Ah...
Azuma.
There you are.
《そこに いたんですね》
(ｼﾞｪﾆﾌｧｰ)⦅あんたは不利なのよ｡
アズマがいるから⦆
And you're at a disadvantage, because Azuma is an evaluator.
Yeah, he's staring at me...
《あ～すっげ～見てるよ》
H-Hey!
おおっとと！大丈夫か!?南波君！
Are you okay, Nanba?
全然 気にすることないよ！
よくある よくある！
Don't worry about it!
This happens all the time!
このイス 調子 悪いんだね！
紫…｡
Probably something wrong with the chair.
Murasaki...
《ちょっと…ゆるめすぎたか？》
I guess I loosened the screw too much?
《なんなんだ…これは…➡
Wh-What's going on?
Oops! Don't forget to keep smiling.
いかん！笑顔キープ》
Why did this happen?
《なんで こんなことに
なったのか➡
思い浮かんだパターンは３つ➡
Three possibilities come to mind.
One, this was Azuma's work, due to his grudge against Hibito.
ねた
１･日々人のことを妬む
いんぼう
吾妻さんの陰謀…ニッ➡
Two, the chair really was worn out.
２･本当に たまたま
イスが壊れかけてた｡➡
Three...
３…➡
夢？》
It's a dream?
《ぐっこの筋肉痛！》
This pain...
うおっハハハ！
(宮田)だ 大丈夫？
A-Are you okay?
《夢ではない》
This isn't a dream.
＜その後の面接は
あまりにも あっけなく➡
The interview itself was very short.
２次試験の時と同じような
内容だった｡➡
The questions were similar to those asked during the second exam.
だからこそ わからなかった＞
That's why I couldn't understand...
《何のための
面接だったんだ？➡
What was the purpose of this interview?
本当に誰か これで
落とされるのか？》
Are they actually judging people with this?
(5 days before launch) Night
Okay, then...
(茄子田)え～ねっ昨日の最終面接
お疲れ様でした｡➡
Thank you for participating in the final interviews.
明日からね 私達も
フロリダへ行きます｡➡
Tomorrow, we will all head to Florida.
そこで３日間 フロリダ観光したら
その翌日 いよいよ➡
After three days of sightseeing,
we'll get to see Hibito take off.
日々人君たちの打ち上げです｡
楽しみだよねぇ～ねえ｡➡
Everyone is excited, right?
Right?
それでは今日はパッとやろうね！
カンパーイ！
So tonight, kick back and relax!
Cheers!
(一同)カンパーイ！
プハァーッ！
(紫)さあ！
Here!
Drink up, Nanba.
どんどん飲もうぜ 南波君！
ど～も いただきます！
Thank you! I will!
Space City...
(茄子田)♪～ 宇宙の街を～
(紫)いや～ねっ おっかしいだろ!!
Right? Isn't that hilarious?
(紫)なっ？ハハハハ！
Yeah?
さあ！
Okay...
プハァーッ！
(女性職員)おはよう 原田君｡
ドリンクお願いね｡
(原田)は～い｡
Good morning Harada.
Could you bring our drinks?
Yes.
ブラック２のミルク入り３…｡
Two black, three with milk, two of which have sugar.
うち 砂糖アリ２
つぶつぶオレンジ１｡
One with orange pulp.
Good morning.
(原田)おはようございます｡
(星加)おう｡
Hey.
ブラックです｡
サンキュウ｡
Black.
Thanks.
それ もう終わったんですよね
ヒューストンでの最終面接｡
We're finished, right?
The final Houston interview
星加さんが前に言ってた➡
was what you meant when you said
｢全てが決まる たった一日｣
ってやつが｡➡
everything would be decided in one day.
もう 誰か決定したかな…｡
Do they know who's been chosen?
残念ながら原田君
そりゃ ハズレだ｡
Unfortunately, Harada, you're wrong.
I wasn't talking about yesterday.
たった一日ってのは
昨日じゃない｡
今日…ちょうど今｡
It's happening today, as we speak.
アイエスエス
そうね ＩＳＳって
400キロ上空を回ってるんだけど➡
That's right.
The ISS orbits at an altitude of 400 km,
その高さじゃ 地球全体の姿は
見られないのよね｡
so you don't get a view of the whole Earth.
(北村)そうなんですか？
Really?
Let's pretend that the Earth is the size of a soccer ball that you're holding in your hands.
地球の大きさを
サッカーボールだとして➡
こう持ってみるでしょ｡
そしたら➡
The ISS would be right above your finger.
その爪の先くらいのラインが
ＩＳＳの高さよ｡
(木崎)だから まん丸の地球を
見たことがある日本人は➡
That's why the only Japanese person to have seen the Earth in its entirety
吾妻さん ただ１人｡
would be Azuma.
(紫)ヘイ！南波君 真壁君
コーラ コーラ！
Hey, Nanba! Makabe!
How about some Coke?
肉にはコーラだよ 君たち！
Coke is perfect with meat.
Thank you very much!
ありがとうございます｡
(ｹﾝｼﾞ)すいません いただきます｡
Don't mind if I do.
Okay...
《さあ～運が悪いのは
どっちだ～!?》
So, which will have the worse luck?
おうえっ!!何だ こりゃ!?
What is this?
くへぇ～！
《やっぱり南波君！》
I knew it would be Nanba!
くさ
このコーラ 腐ってねえ？
そう？
Has this Coke gone bad?
Has it?
(紫)ふっふっふっ 南波君…｡
Nanba...
悪かった｡君のはコーラじゃない
コーヒーだ｡
Sorry, yours isn't Coke.
It's coffee.
Huh?
きょうみ
いや～実に興味深いよね｡
Yes, this is fascinating...
コーラのボトルで
コーヒーを飲むと 人は➡
If someone drinks coffee out of a Coke bottle,
｢腐ってる｣と判断するんだね｡
勉強になった！
they'll assume the Coke has gone bad.
How educational!
《な…なんなんだ この人は｡
まるで➡
Wh-What's wrong with him?
He's a mischievous little kid.
｢いたずらッコ｣じゃないか！》
てごわ
《手強いぞ…紫三世!!》
おぅえ！ハハハッ｡
Murasaki Sansei could be a tough one...
(紫)まっじ～ギャハハ｡
これ 我ながらないわ～｡
Tastes horrible!
This was definitely a mistake.
《紫のヤツ…また遊んでやがるな｡
頼むからマジメにやれ｡➡
Murasaki's fooling around again.
Can't you be serious?
ここでの俺たちの｢役割｣を
忘れんなよ》
Don't forget that we have a job to do.
うわぁ～！
《わっ うまい！うわ これも！
これも うまい！》
Oh, this is good.
So is this...
And this, too!
(森嶋)実は僕 木崎さんの
隠れファンなんですよ｡
I'm actually a closet fan of yours, Kisaki.
Huh? I'm doing a bad job of hiding it?
え？別に隠れてないって？
ダッハハハ！ごもっとも！
You've got that right!
Th-Thank you very much.
あ ありがとうございます｡
《おやじだぁ…》
So lame...
(森嶋)わさび いりません？
Want some wasabi?
い いえ…｡
N-No thank you...
When you add wasabi to something greasy,
わさびと脂分を一緒に食べると➡
the wasabi isn't as spicy, and the food isn't as greasy.
わさびは辛くなくなって
脂分は さっぱりするんですよ｡➡
So it's perfect with steak.
だから ステーキなんかと
合わせると うまい｡
こりゃ ステキ！
Steak on a stake.
しもふ
ただ 日本の霜降りとは合うけど
こっちの赤身の肉と食べると➡
But this only works with Japanese shimofuri beef.
It has a strong kick if you try it with American red meat.
ツーンとくるんですよ｡
アーン モグモグ…｡
ツーン！ほら きたぁ!!
There it is!
(紫)なあ 南波君
２人だけの話さぁ➡
Hey, Nanba. Just between you and me...
ショージキ みんなのこと
どう思ってんの？
What's your honest opinion of the other candidates?
バッサリ言っちゃいよ｡
Speak your mind.
い～んすか 言っちゃって？
いいよ いいよ｡
もう全部 終わったんだしさ｡
Is it really okay?
Of course it is... Everything's over now.
みんなが どんな奴か
聞かせてくれよ｡
Tell me what everyone's like.
まず あそこにデカイの
いるでしょ｡
(紫)新田君ね｡
First, you see the big guy over there?
Nitta, right?
見た目通り スポーツマンタイプで
筋肉と血管が自慢の男ですよ｡
He's athletic, with plenty of muscle, as you can see.
クールぶってタフガイを
演じてますけどね 実は…｡
He likes to act cool and play the tough guy.
However...
携帯の待ち受けが…ネコです｡
意外！
His cell phone wallpaper
is a cat.
Shocking!
ありえないでしょ？
ありえねぇな！
Hard to believe, right?
Definitely...
北村さんは小柄だけど
気が強くて しっかり者です｡
Kitamura is small, but she's outspoken and organized.
ただ…くしゃみする時
意地でも口を閉ざしてるから…｡
However...
When she sneezes, she insists on keeping her mouth shut,
｢ぶ～っ｣って言います｡
so it sounds funny.
ほう…｡
Oh...
森嶋さんは 自分の話をするのが
大好きですね｡
Morishima loves to talk about himself.
前に話した内容を繰り返すことが
多々あります｡
He tends to repeat himself a lot.
くちびる
話す前に必ず唇を
ひとなめします｡
He always licks his lips before he starts.
And he'll suddenly change the subject for no reason.
みゃくらく
あと 脈略なく
話題が突然 変わります｡
(紫)ほお…｡
《こいつ…よく見てる！》
This guy is
really observant.
きみ
(紫)じゃあ南波君 君から見て➡
Then, Nanba...
In your opinion,
一番 宇宙飛行士に
ふさわしいと思うのは誰だ？
who would make the best astronaut?
一番ふさわしいと思うのは…｡
The person who would make the best astronaut...
ケンジです｡
would be Kenji.
《なるほど》
I see.
でも 一番なってほしいと
願うのは…｡
But the person I'd most like to become an astronaut
せりかさん｡
is Serika.
ん～ところが 実は
一番なりたがってるのは…｡
But the person who wants it the most...
俺です｡
is me.
《もう面接も終わったんだから
早く帰らせろよ｡➡
If the interview's over, they should let us leave.
こっちの食事は僕には合わない》
I don't like the food here.
口に合わないのか 溝口君？
あんまり食べてないじゃないか｡
Do you not like the food, Mizoguchi?
You haven't eaten much.
いえ…おいしいんですけど
控えてるんで｡
No, it's good.
I'm trying to watch what I eat.
そうなんだ｡ところで溝口君➡
I understand.
By the way, Mizoguchi...
あそこに新田君っているだろ｡
You see Nitta over there?
Huh?
あいつって どんな奴？
What's he like?
(星加)残念ながら原田君
そりゃ ハズレだ｡➡
Unfortunately, Harada,
you're wrong.
I wasn't talking about yesterday.
たった一日ってのは
昨日じゃない｡
Huh?
今日…ちょうど今｡
It's happening today, as we speak.
(星加)ＮＡＳＡでの最終面接は
フェイクだ｡➡
The final interview held at NASA is a decoy.
一応 それらしくはやるが➡
They go through the motions, but it has no impact.
そこでの評価は
今までと変わらない｡
ＮＡＳＡでの面接の役割は➡
The objective is to convince the candidates that they're done.
｢これで全て終わった｣と
思わせること｡
(星加)今頃…肩の荷が下りきって
｢素｣に近い受験者達が➡
Right now, they're letting loose and relaxing, while being carefully monitored.
ことこま
事細かにチェックされてるはずだ｡
今日 今…｡
Today... As we speak.
げんえき
そこで現役の飛行士達は 自分達の
感覚にしたがって受験者を見る｡➡
The active astronauts will talk to the candidates and make their decisions.
目の前の奴と宇宙で生活を
送っていけそうか｡➡
"Would this person be able to live in space?"
自分の命を こいつに
預けることができるか｡
"Would I trust this person with my life?"
ちょっかん
そういうの直感で
わかっちゃうらしいよ➡
These are things astronauts know instinctively.
宇宙飛行士っていうのは｡
新田君ですか？う～ん…
彼とは別の班だったし➡
Nitta?
He was on a different team,
まだ あまり話してないんで
よく わからないですけど…｡
so I haven't gotten a chance to really talk to him...
…そうか｡
I see.
Nitta Reiji
Athlete, cool
Good listener
According to Nanba, cell phone
wallpaper is a cat
Morishima Shigeo
Likes to talk
Keeps talking about self when drunk
According to Nanba,
licks his lips before talking
Makabe Kenji
Earnest, old-fashioned
っし！
Yeah!
おっ ミヤッチ｡
(宮田)おう｡➡
Hey, Miya-chi.
Hey.
紫 お前 南波君に吾妻さんには
話しかけるなとか言ってたろ｡
Murasaki, you told Nanba to stay away from Azuma?
あ 聞こえてた？ワリィ｡
Oh, you heard that?
Sorry.
つい不利なアイツが
かわいそ～に思えてさ｡
I felt bad because he's in a bad position, so I wanted to help.
なんか軽く助け船 出しちゃった｡
気持ちはわかるが
どうやら逆効果だぞ｡
I get where you're coming from, but it had the opposite effect.
Huh? Eh?
(紫)《バカか 南波六太!!》
Are you stupid, Nanba Mutta?!
The lens inside my eyes
went completely out of focus when I saw you
The signs of love flooded the occipital lobe of my cerebrum
The words the left side of my brain produced
brought my vocal cords to reverberation
Vigorously my confession traversed my tongue
May I love you?
May I really love you?
May I be beside you? (The concentration of my hormones rose)
(Dopamine overwhelmed me)
Can I hold your hand? (My blood circulation powered up)
Next time, on
Space Brothers
#27 One Question
(紫)＜このパーティー
俺たち現役飛行士は➡
The active astronauts are using this party to observe the candidates.
受験者を
ひそかにチェックしてる＞
＜そこで吾妻さんに話しかける
なんて ばかか？南波六太＞
You must be an idiot, Nanba Mutta, to approach Azuma!
Nice to meet you! I'm Nanba Mutta.
＜はじめまして 南波六太です｡➡
Thank you for taking good care of my little brother, Hibito.
弟の日々人が いつもお世話になり
ありがとうございます＞
＜今後とも どうぞ
よろしくお願い申し上げます＞
I look forward to working with you!
(紫)＜年賀状か‼＞
Are you writing a New Year's card?
Next time, on Space Brothers:
"One Question"
One question...
＜一つだけ 一つだけ答えてくれ➡
I have one question for you.
死ぬ覚悟は あるか？＞
Are you prepared to die?
(日々人)パンパカパーン！
今週の➡
This Week's Space Photo
Heading out to space!
This week's space photo!
宇宙写真です！
カッコイイ！
Cool stuff!